<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document><h1>How to...</h1>
<p>Example scripts, how to do a specific task or explaining a single PageBot functions.</p>
<h2>Align elements</h2>
<p><img alt="gallery/AlignElements.png" src="gallery/AlignElements.png" /><br />
The script shows the different alignment conditions. <em>Left2Left()</em> goes to the left padding. <em>Left2LeftSide()</em> goes to the left side of the document.<br />
<em>page.solve()</em> tries to solve any condition that does not fit the defined optimal value.</p>
<p><img alt="gallery/AlignElementsUI.png" src="gallery/AlignElementsUI.png" /></p>
<p>The Variable UI window shows how to implement checkbox and slider to manipulate certain values in the page. </p>
<h2>Scale an image (DrawBot)</h2>
<p>Since image scaling in DrawBot needs to be done by canvas scaling, the position of the image needs to be scaled in reverse. This examples shows how to do it.</p>
<p><img alt="gallery/cookbot1-50.png" src="gallery/cookbot1-50.png" /></p>
<h2>Sierpinski Square (DrawBot)</h2>
<p>Example of an animated gif in DrawBot.</p>
<p><img alt="gallery/SierpinskiSquare.gif" src="gallery/SierpinskiSquare.gif" /></p>
<h2>Draw Red Rectangle Center Page</h2>
<p>Simple demo to show the positioning of a colored rectangle centered on the page. Also the alignment origin of the rectangle is centered. The view draws cropmarks, page frame and rectangle origin marker.</p>
<p><img alt="gallery/DrawRedRectCenterPage.png" src="gallery/DrawRedRectCenterPage.png" /></p>
<h2>Draw View Page Frame</h2>
<p>Simple test to show the working of view and page. Option Variable checkbox to set the origin to top or bottom.</p>
<h2>Draw Quadratic Glyph</h2>
<p>Shows how to load a Truetype font and draw a glyph with quadratic Bézier curves with the cubic Bézier curves that PageBot uses.</p>
<h2>Use text flows</h2>
<p>The example shows two floating colums of text, where th overflow of one goes into the other. If the second one also overflows, the remaining text goes into a column on the third page.</p>
<p><img alt="gallery/DrawRedRectCenterPage.png" src="gallery/UseTextFlows.png" /></p></document>