<document><h1>Lemon Herb Chicken</h1>
<h2>Ingredients</h2>
<p>SERVINGS 8-10 UNITS US</p>
<ul>
<li>1⁄2 cup white sugar</li>
<li>1 (14 ounce) can pumpkin pie filling</li>
<li>1 (12 ounce) can evaporated milk</li>
<li>1 (5 ounce) can sweetened condensed milk</li>
<li>6 eggs</li>
<li>1⁄2 cup white sugar</li>
<li>1 teaspoon vanilla extract</li>
<li>1 teaspoon allspice</li>
</ul>
<p>On Sale Near You See what's on sale in recipes and in your Grocery List.</p>
<p>Find stores<br />
Pumpkin Soup, 15 Ways</p>
<h2>Directions</h2>
<p>Preheat oven to 375 degrees. Melt 1/2 cup sugar in an aluminum loaf pan and heat over medium heat. Continue to cook until it caramelizes, being careful to not burn the sugar.</p>
<p><img alt="lemonHerbChicke" src="images/cookbot5.jpg" title="" /></p>
<p>Fill a large pot of water with about 1 inch of water and place over medium heat. Move the aluminum pan into the large pot and set into the water.<br />
Combine the pumpkin pie filling, evaporated milk, condensed milk, eggs, 1/2 cup sugar, vanilla, and allspice in a blender, blend until smooth. Pour the mixture into the loaf pan.<br />
Bake in preheated oven until a knife inserted in the center comes out clean, about 1 hour. Refrigerate for at least 3 hours, or overnight.<br />
Run a knife along the edge of the loaf pan to loosen the flan. Invert the pan onto a serving plate and tap to release the dessert.</p>
<h1>Arizona: Cran-Turkey Enchiladas</h1>
<h2>Ingredients</h2>
<p>SERVINGS 8 UNITS US<br />
nonstick cooking spray<br />
2 -2 1⁄2 cups shredded cooked turkey<br />
1 (16 ounce) can whole berry cranberry sauce<br />
1 (15 ounce) can black beans, rinsed and drained<br />
1 1⁄2 cups bottled salsa<br />
1 cup shredded colby-monterey jack cheese (4 oz.)<br />
1⁄2 cup sour cream<br />
3 green onions, sliced<br />
1⁄4 cup snipped fresh cilantro<br />
1 teaspoon ground cumin<br />
1⁄2 teaspoon salt<br />
1⁄2 teaspoon ground black pepper<br />
8 whole wheat flour tortillas or 8 whole flour tortillas<br />
1 teaspoon bottled hot pepper sauce<br />
On Sale Near You<br />
See what's on sale in recipes and in your Grocery List.</p>
<p>Find stores<br />
 Turkey<br />
Turkey</p>
<h2>Directions</h2>
<p>Preheat oven to 350 degrees F. Lightly coat a 3-quart rectangular baking dish with cooking spray; set aside.<br />
For filling, in a large bowl stir together turkey, half the cranberry sauce, beans, 1/2 cup of the salsa, 3/4 cup of the cheese, sour cream, green onions, cilantro, cumin, salt, and pepper.</p>
<p><img alt="lemonHerbChicke" src="images/cookbot14.jpg" title="" /></p>
<p>Spoon about 2/3 cup filling on each tortilla. Roll up tortillas around filling. Place, seam sides down, in prepared dish; set aside.<br />
For sauce, in bowl stir together remaining cranberry sauce, remaining salsa, and hot pepper sauce. Spoon over filled tortillas. Cover with foil. Bake for 45 minutes. Uncover; top with remaining cheese. Bake 5 to 10 minutes more or until heated through and cheese is melted. Sprinkle with additional cilantro and green onions.</p></document>